KEVIN JOSE

kevjose@gmail.com • www.kevinjose.net

+447946033867

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Researcher with over 6 years of international experience in mathematical modelling, numerical computing and analysis. Able to rapidly acquire new skills, evidenced by diverse research endeavours spanning from smart materials to applied machine learning. Industry exposure in technical roles and as a management consultant. Discovered a novel wave-scattering phenomenon during PhD.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Cambridge

March 2023 - Present

Cambridge, UK

Postdoctoral Research Associate

Research Areas: Machine Learning, Material Science.

- · Developed an autoencoder-based approach for efficient latent representation of material science data.
- · Created a genetic algorithm-based routine for generating balanced counts from a materials database.
- · Implemented numerous deep-learning architectures and related training and regularization methods.
- · Two research manuscripts under preparation. Gave a research talk at EPFL, Lausanne.

University of Southampton

May 2019 - Dec 2022

Marie Skłodowska-Curie Fellow

Southampton, UK

Research Areas: Mathematical Modelling, Computational Mechanics.

- · Numerical and theoretical analysis of stochastic differential equations and PDEs in the context of mechanics.
- · Created a mathematical model for heat-exchanger dynamics, then converted to a user-friendly GUI tool.
- · Developed a software pipeline for automated setup and scheduling of over 8000 FEA jobs on High-Performance Clusters, integrating BASH, Python, MATLAB, and ANSYS scripts.
- Discovered a new scattering phenomenon in waves travelling in random elastic media.

New York University

School of Engineering Fellow

Aug 2017 - Oct 2018

Brooklyn, USA

Research Areas: Stochastic Modelling, Smart Materials

- · Stochastic modelling of fish behaviour using a mean-reverting diffusion process with a stochastic jump term.
- · Demonstrated a method to enhance the actuation of ionic polymer metal composites. Designed and fabricated the high-power electronics required to conduct experiments.

INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

Boston Consulting Group

Nov 2018 - May 2019

New Delhi, India

· Worked on a profit turn-around project for a large steel manufacturer (>1.5 Bn GBP revenue).

- · Identified process bottlenecks in 6 production plants from time-motion studies, interviews and data analysis.
- · Synthesized findings and made recommendations to C-level executives.
- · Wrote a Python script to automate data extraction, cleaning and visualization of defect reports in a production facility. This led to the identification of the root causes of >80 \% of the defects.

EDUCATION

Associate

University of Southampton

Jun 2019 - Jun 2023

Doctor of Philosophy, Computational Engineering and Design Group

BT-MT Dual Degree, Department of Mechanical Engineering

Southampton, UK

Marie Skłodowska-Curie Fellow

Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur

Jul 2012 - Aug 2017 Kanpur, India

Minor in Control Systems Engineering

PROGRAMMING/COMPUTING SKILLS

Python (PyTorch, Numpy, Pandas, Tkinter, sklearn), MATLAB, Mathematica, HPCs

RELEVANT COURSES

Math Advanced Partial Differential Equations, Stochastic Calculus
Computing Applied Numerical Methods, Biostatistics, Optimization Methods

SECONDMENTS/INTERNSHIPS

Vestas aircoil	Jan 2020 - Sep 2021
Visiting PhD Student	$Lem,\ Denmark$
Singapore University of Technology and Design	May 2016 - Jul 2016
Summer Intern	Upper Changi, Singapore
	Try comings, and are
Whirlpool Global Technology & Engineering Center	May 2015 - Jul 2015
Summer Intern	$Pune,\ India$

AWARDS, FELLOWSHIPS & SCHOLASTIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Marie Skłodowska-Curie Fellow, University of Southampton	2019
Best PhD Qualifying Exam, NYU Tandon School of Engineering	2018
School of Engineering Fellowship, NYU Tandon School of Engineering	2017
Best Intern Award, Whirlpool Global Technology & Engineering Center	2015
Merit-cum-Means Scholarship, Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur	2014
IIT-Joint Entrance Exam All India Rank 792 out of ~0.47 million candidates (99.8 %ile)	
KVPY Fellowship, National fellowship for students interested in research careers (Declined)	2012

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

$\star PLoS\ ONE$	Branched flows of flexural elastic waves in non-uniform cylindrical shells.	2023
$\star Nature\ Commun.\ Phys.$	Branching flows of flexural waves in non-uniform elastic plates.	2022
$\dagger Ex. \; Mech. \; Lett.$	How far does a fold go?	2021
$\star J.\ Acoust.\ Soc.\ Am.$	Acoustics of idakkā: An Indian snare drum with definite pitch.	2018
$\ddagger Appl. \ Phys. \ Lett.$	Enhancing the deformation range of ionic polymer metal composites	2018
	through electrostatic actuation.	

^{*:} As first author; ‡: As co-first author; †: As second author.

SELECTED RESEARCH TALKS

EPFL	Open Databases Integration for Materials Design	2023
Univ. College London	Elasticity Day	2022
Univ. of Oxford	18th European Mechanics of Materials Conference	2022
$Univ.\ of\ Southampton$	ISVR Research Seminar	2022
$NUI\ Galway$	11th European Solid Mechanics Conference	2022
$\S \mathit{Univ.}\ of\ \mathit{Cambridge}$	Elasticity Day	2021
§: Delivered online.		

MISCELLANEOUS

- · Organizer of the InDEStruct Workshop (~70 attendees.)
- · Reviewer for The European Physical Journal Plus (Springer)